<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><projectform><network>Alliance</network><application>E-vet</application><date_filed>2013-03-07</date_filed><version>1.0</version><pef_send_by>UAALT Anna Isaieva</pef_send_by><pef_sender_email>alterplace@gmail.com</pef_sender_email><organization>Alternative V</organization><organization_code>UAALT</organization_code><projects><project id="6e1a7b9162eeec6c2961e493fed116e9                  "><code>ALT-01</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-06-02</start_date><end_date>2013-06-16</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE I</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>19</min_age><max_age>29</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>5</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. There is water and electricity on the project site. Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by children (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>we expect volunteers to be actively involved in the life of Scoutville. You will take part in administrating project site (checking accommodation facilities for children etc). International volunteers will help in organizing and leading clubs, workshops. If you have your own ideas what to suggest as a theme of a workshop/club/meeting i you are always welcome Please, mention your ideas for possible activities and your previous experience in motivation letter.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>volunteers will be accommodated in 2 tents (1 tent for 3 persons).  Food will be provided (or prepared by volunteers) three times per day.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is strictly forbidden on the project site. Smoking in front of children is not acceptable. We are waiting for volunteers who are interested to work with children, have good ideas and need space to implement them. Motivation letter is required Please, describe in ML which skills you want to share with campers.                   On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together with the campleader will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus, one way ticket cost i around 3 euro.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>2</numvol_m><numvol_f>3</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>Motivation letter is required</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="5973d3856fad7adac57510c1268377d3                  "><code>ALT-12</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>RENO,</work><start_date>2013-08-04</start_date><end_date>2013-08-17</end_date><name>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>30</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>12</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>The camp is situated in the suburban part of Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy. This town has a rich history and a lot of places to see. It is situated on the banks of one of the most beautiful rivers in Ukraine - the Dnieper, 100 km to the south-east of Kyiv i the capital of Ukraine. Pereyaslav-Khmelnystskyi is one of the most important places in Ukrainian history.  Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy has existed since the 10th century. It was a border stronghold of the Kievian Rus state and was overrun by Tatars in 1239. The town began to recover in the 16th century and emerged as a site of Ukrainian Cossack culture. In 1654, Bohdan Khmelnytskyi and his Cossacks met at Pereyaslav to agree that Ukraine, for protection against Poland, becomes a protectorate of Russia i breakdown in the Ukrainian history.     There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in the city, so volunteers will enjoy this place.Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated, complete with gardens and flowers around the houses with whitewashed walls and thatch roofs. In the houses you find icons and decorative towels  exactly the way it looked in the times of old. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_partner> <descr_work>Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is integral part of national Ukrainian heritage and is protected by special law. Alternative-V has been organizing this workcamp every year since 1996 repairing the historical objects and cultural monuments, participating in the work on the territory of the historic and cultural recreation area in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy. Volunteers will help the staff of the Museum of Ukrainian Folk Architecture through different activities to restore the museum exhibits and to clean the territory of the museum.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>will be provided in dormitory of the local vocational school. Food will be provided 2 times per day. Breakfast will be prepared by volunteers themselves.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, 100 km to the south-east of Kyiv.Leisure time: As it was mentioned above there are a lot of museums in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers can explore the history and culture of the Central Ukraine. Trip to Kyiv (2 Euro one way by bus) can be organized. Sunbathing and swimming in the Dnipro River and the lake are possible.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>---</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>6</numvol_m><numvol_f>6</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes></notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="b5c14899f29da2810b30b2b9923eaf4d                  "><code>ALT-07</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-07-05</start_date><end_date>2013-07-18</end_date><name>SUMMER WITH ENGLISH II</name><location>KHARKIV</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>99</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>4</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>Sports summer centre  Boyko school  is situated in a picturesque place on the bank of the lake, 30 km from Kharkiv (second largest city in Ukraine and its first capital), eastern part of Ukraine. The Center was founded in 1987 on the territory of the former duke s estate. On the territory of the Center there is a pond with a lot of fish i so you can go fishing there. There also are stables with 12 horses, a riding school for children. The camp hosts about 200 children at a time. The camp works by the program of the summer English language school.</descr_partner> <descr_work>Each volunteer will be accommodated together with one Ukrainian leader in the camp next to children rooms. The main task of the volunteers will be to help in organising everyday life of the camp and leisure time activities, such as workshops, sport competitions, contests, activities connected with culture, history, traditions of the volunteers  countries. The volunteers will also assist teachers in teaching English in the course of lessons. Volunteers will not be provided with a ready plan for the lessons or activities. Everything is up to the volunteers. We expect from volunteers new ideas and enthusiasm in organising children s leisure time to make it meaningful and fun. Every volunteer must be ready to help children in organising the Day of Culture of the volunteer s country (national games, songs, dances, recipes of the national food i should be easy to cook). If you have experience, and most important - desire to work with children, this project is for YOU</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will be accommodated in rooms with 4 beds. Simple accommodation; toilet and shower with warm water are near the rooms. Food will be provided in the camp canteen three times a day.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>30 km from Kharkiv.  Kharkiv is the second largest city in Ukraine and its first capital. It can truly be named a Ukrainian megapolis. It is situated in North-East of Ukraine in the confluence of three rivers. Its population is 1 470 000 people. It is one of the biggest scientific and cultural centers. Kharkiv is the city of students and has 80 higher educational establishments. The city is famous for its great traditions and extraordinary historical past. In 2004 Kharkiv celebrated its 350th anniversary.  Here you can find some information about Kharkiv     http://www.kharkov.ua/index-e.phtmlLeisure Time: Lots of sport facilities are available, in the evening cultural meetings with the campers and staff will be organized, sightseeing, excursions around Kharkiv city, disco and everything what we will be able to create for ourselves to make our camp exciting.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>Dates of projects can vary by 1-2 days (precise dates will be confirmed at the beginning of April).</descr_requirements><airport>HRK</airport><station>Kharkiv</station><numvol_m>2</numvol_m><numvol_f>2</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>1</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>49.9935000</lat_project><lng_project>36.2303830</lng_project><notes></notes><lat_station>49.9935000</lat_station><lng_station>36.2303830</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="5670f4c2644508978b4be11c19dc5a74                  "><code>ALT-15</code><project_type>TEE</project_type><work>SPOR,</work><start_date>2013-06-17</start_date><end_date>2013-07-01</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE FOR TEENAGERS II</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>14</min_age><max_age>16</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>10</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. Pine forest on the bank of picturesque river of the river creates an unforgettable atmosphere of living in nature.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>One of the main ideas of the camp is to teach through the practical work, making children s holiday active, entertaining, informative and helpful. The camp program is aimed not only at the organization of children s rest, but also on education of children. Learning is very various, from the basics of safe behavior to the training of leadership and oratory. Every child and teenager can find in the Forest Academy something really good for himself.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>in triple double-layer tents that protect from rain and insects. All tents are placed on pallets to raise them above the ground, so children are protected from moisture and dirt.Camp is ensured with uninterrupted water and power supply. Water from the source of Jurassic period is tested and certified according to the requirements of sanitary-epidemiological service.Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by campers (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire 4 times per day. We offer children to participate in cooking food to get so useful practical skills and making their own culinary experiments.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>Extra fee: 300 Euros.Remarks: On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>5</numvol_m><numvol_f>5</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>EXTRA FEE - 300 EUROS</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="b56d7b74a77754d8a55e0fdaf07bc9cb                  "><code>ALT-03</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-06-17</start_date><end_date>2013-07-01</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE II</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>19</min_age><max_age>29</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>5</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. There is water and electricity on the project site. Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by children (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>we expect volunteers to be actively involved in the life of Scoutville. You will take part in administrating project site (checking accommodation facilities for children etc). International volunteers will help in organizing and leading clubs, workshops. If you have your own ideas what to suggest as a theme of a workshop/club/meeting i you are always welcome Please, mention your ideas for possible activities and your previous experience in motivation letter.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>volunteers will be accommodated in 2 tents (1 tent for 3 persons).  Food will be provided (or prepared by volunteers) three times per day.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is strictly forbidden on the project site. Smoking in front of children is not acceptable. We are waiting for volunteers who are interested to work with children, have good ideas and need space to implement them. Motivation letter is required Please, describe in ML which skills you want to share with campers.                   On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together with the campleader will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus, one way ticket cost i around 3 euro.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>2</numvol_m><numvol_f>3</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>Motivation letter is required</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="5afa8d1d2244db5cfb3d101cca9c145c                  "><code>ALT-11</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>RENO,</work><start_date>2013-07-28</start_date><end_date>2013-08-09</end_date><name>HIV CENTER FOR KIDS</name><location>RUBIZHNE</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>30</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>8</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>Project partners: Peace Corps Volunteers, NGO  Djerelo .Project: Ukraine is occupying one of the leading places in Europe in the spread of HIV. The most critical situation is in the eastern regions of Ukraine and on the south. Lugansk region (the most eastern region of Ukraine) due to its specificity is a leader in Ukraine in this sphere. Lugansk region is a huge industrial area with all problems typical for such zones: pollution, poor ecological situation, limited opportunities for local people. Local youth have just few ways of spending their free time. Together with local activists, NGO Djerelo and Peace Corp Volunteers whose project is based in Rubizhne we decided to help to create space for meetings, clubs etc for local youth and children. In previous year international volunteers together with local youth created and decorated children s playground. Experience of hosting foreign volunteers was unforgettable for local community.          In Rubizhne is situated HIV/Aids Regional Daycares Centre for youth and children (age 5-15 years old). Centre offers services for people living with HIV/AIDS and provides social rehabilitation for at-risk members of the community. Daily Centre serves around 160 persons. Many children are orphans and come from problem families. Centre administration tries to provide youth with different workshops, clubs, trainings and classes to vary leisure time and wake their interests to something new. This year administration decides to introduce intercultural atmosphere to everyday s routine of the clients of the Centre.      We plan that group of international volunteers together with 20 children who come from the poorest environment together will work and spend free time together.  Also we plan to involve local youth activists.         Ultimately, the project is aimed at both renovating, as well as transferring technical and leadership skills to local youth volunteers. We plan to have study part i international volunteers will have an opportunity to learn more about HIV infection, situation with HIV/AIDS in Ukraine and also share information about situation in their native countries. Also we plan meetings with local youth and schoolchildren.         The project is really important for the local community and for volunteers who want to help and to see results of their work. For many children the Centre is the only place where they can feel safely, eat and have a rest. We hope that contacts with international volunteers will make days of those children brighter.</descr_partner> <descr_work>the task for the workcamp is to renovate and improve children s playground which was built by previous workcamp.  The second task will be decorating of internal space (rooms, halls) of Daycares Centre in a creative way (pictures, symbols etc.). It is possibility to organise presentation about situation with HIV/AIDS in countries of participants.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>volunteers will be housed in Daycares Centre in rooms. Food will be provided two times per day. Breakfast will be prepared by volunteers.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: town Rubizhne, Lugansk region, UkraineTerminal: LuganskLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  Volunteers will be given the opportunity to swim at the local lake, barbeque in the forest, enjoy outdoor sports. There is a possibility to spend weekend in children summer camp in 15 km from city Rubizhne.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is not welcomed on the project.                  On the first day of the project (28.07.13) volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kyiv and together will take an overnight train to the project site. Trip will take around 14 hours, one way ticket costs around 25 Euros.</descr_requirements><airport>VSG</airport><station>Lugansk</station><numvol_m>4</numvol_m><numvol_f>4</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>49.0108620</lat_project><lng_project>38.3740710</lng_project><notes></notes><lat_station>48.5740410</lat_station><lng_station>39.3078150</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="0a192f1808d8ccff7a862415a963a038                  "><code>ALT-08</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>RENO,</work><start_date>2013-07-08</start_date><end_date>2013-07-19</end_date><name>PARKLIFE AND WALKING ROUTES</name><location>ZAPORIZHYA</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>29</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>8</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year was announced a year of local tourism development in a small village of Chkalovo in Zaporizhia province. Local authorities in cooperation with regional tourism club  Tavria  are working on improvements of leisure activities infrastructure and general tourism attractiveness of the area. International volunteers are invited to join local activists and teenagers help with various manual tasks in the village and to help in creating walking/bike paths to the nearby villages.</descr_partner> <descr_work>various tasks in recreational parks in Chkalovo and closest villages: cleaning, cutting bushes, planting flowers, painting benches, rebuilding walking ways; maintenance of playground for kids, other sport grounds. Important part of the project is dedicated to work on tourism routes between the nearby villages. Group will clean the paths, put description tables, mark the path and organize rest places: put benches, tables etc. If you are fond of photography take your camera for taking shots along the routes. They can later be used for the presentations and included to a tourism map of the region. During the project international group will work together with local teenagers. Types of work may vary depending on raw material possibilities as well as weather condition.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>in school. Sleeping bag is needed.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>village Chkalovo, Vesele region, Zaporizhzhya province, southeastern Ukraine. The village is located about 20km from Vesele, 142 km from Zaporizhia and about 130 km from the Sea of Azov.Group trips to a mysterious Stone Grave National historic archaeology reserve and to The Popov Castle (a castle-like rural residence turned in 1993 into a historical architecture museum) are planned for a week-end. You may as well discover the city of Zaporizhia and Khortitsia island situated in the middle of the city and believed to be a cradle of Ukrainian Cossacks. Meetings with locals will be organized through the workcamp program and you will have a chance to go for cultural exchange and enjoy Ukrainian local food and hospitality traditional for the region as well.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>1) Motivation letter is required 2) please notice that project location is a typical Ukrainian rural area, work may be physically demanding sometimes, that s why we ask you to write a short motivation letter showing your interest in the project and willingness to take the challenge.</descr_requirements><airport>OZH</airport><station>Zaporizhzhya</station><numvol_m>4</numvol_m><numvol_f>4</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project></lat_project><lng_project></lng_project><notes>Motivation letter is required</notes><lat_station>47.8388000</lat_station><lng_station>35.1395670</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project> <project id="6caca9e1d8e22ce0600a0a1e4df12e88                  "><code>ALT-10</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>RENO,</work><start_date>2013-07-22</start_date><end_date>2013-08-03</end_date><name>KHARKIV OLD CIRCUS</name><location>KHARKIV</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>99</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>12</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>The history of the Kharkiv Old circus dates back to the year 1905. It was the first theater-circus not only in Kharkiv, but on the whole territory of the former USSR. After Kharkiv circus moved in a new building in April of 1975, The Circus Administration occupied the former Old Circus building.      Except of creative stage work with professional artists a Child and youth circus art studio  Old circus  has been working on the base of the Circus Administration for 11 years so far which is famous in our city, country and internationally. For 10 years more than 300 young 6-16 years old creative, strong and brave admirers of art have been studying in this studio. More than 30 students have closely connected their lives with circus and they are working now with professional artists in  State Circus Company of Ukraine  and in other circus group teams as well.      And it is not the final result of our educational work with growing up generation of young citizens of Kharkiv.  The main thing is that hundred young hearts are taught to love and appreciate the beauty, alienated from streets and negative tendencies that so often influence the development of new generation of citizens of Ukraine.</descr_partner> <descr_work>The Old circus is located in the old area of Kharkiv. We will help to restore the old building of circus: patio. Also we are preparing patio for concreting, sealing and filling gravel. We will have to clean and put in order everything inside. Some cleaning, weeding, work is also included. We will work in the place where every brick is penetrated with history; we will touch directly the spirit of the artistry, which is passing the time</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>student s dormitory (rooms for 3-6 persons with kitchen, common toilet sink, showers are in a nearest building 2-minutes walk from the dormitory). Meals - 3 times per day, prepared by volunteers.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Kharkiv is the second largest city in Ukraine and its first capital. It can truly be named a Ukrainian megapolis. It s situated in North-East of Ukraine in the confluence of three rivers.  Its population is 1 470 000 people. It s one of the biggest scientific and cultural centers. Kharkiv is the city of students and has 80 higher educational establishments. The city is famous for its great traditions and extraordinary historical past. In 2009 Kharkiv celebrated its 355th anniversary.  Here you can find some information about Kharkiv:  http://www.kharkov.ua/index-e.phtmlactivities in the group, intercultural learning, meetings with Ukrainian students, sightseeing, sport and cultural activities, disco, swimming pool, rollerblade, picnics, swimming and paddling in river and everything what we will able to create for ourselves to make our camp exciting.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>---</descr_requirements><airport>HRK</airport><station>Kharkiv</station><numvol_m>6</numvol_m><numvol_f>6</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>49.9935000</lat_project><lng_project>36.2303830</lng_project><notes></notes><lat_station>49.9935000</lat_station><lng_station>36.2303830</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="7245be78faf4d877a42226136103d8fd                  "><code>ALT-05</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-06-24</start_date><end_date>2013-07-07</end_date><name>STEP FORWARD: 6 LIFE LESSONS</name><location>KHARTZYSK</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>99</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>10</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>Our partner  Shag vpered  (Step forward) i is a local NGO, which has the main aim i to activate young people on the local level. They organize different trainings, events, charity actions for youth and children and with youth. Their biggest achievement is the creation of the 1st Youth Center in the south-eastern Ukraine, which prepares coordinators of volunteer groups.        Khartsyzk is situated 30 km from Donetsk, regional center. It has a population of about 65 000 inhabitants. There are several schools and high-schools. Industry in a town is the strong side of it. There are several plants, such as pipe plant, engineering plant, furniture plant, bread factory etc. This camp will be organized for the first time. This town has never seen a group of foreigners from different countries, neither the children. Most of the children come from the poor families and they might never get a chance to go abroad and to see other s lives. Playing games with these children will have a long time impact; give them an opportunity to learn more about the outside world and to learn possibilities, which they have when they grow older. It is very important to activate local children and youth to work for the local community, to promote volunteering and active eco life style. For the local NGO it will give a chance to attract more donors and find volunteers to help out even after the camp is over.</descr_partner> <descr_work>we invite volunteers for intercultural exchange with the local children (12-16 years old). The idea is to develop and teach 6 life lessons on different topics (e.i. team building, ecological education etc). We want to provide open space for volunteers to bring their ideas and help to implement them. Volunteers will have 2 days for each topic: 1 day to prepare and 1 day to perform.  One of the lessons will be taught to the leaders and active volunteers of the regional partners-NGOs. The last 3-4 days will be in the regional landscape park Zuevka, where volunteers together with the representatives of NGOs will spend in the eco-style, living in tents and cooking in teams. Special program will be prepared for that part.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will live in the dormitory, 5-6 people in a room. All the facilities are available. Food will be provided 3 times a day in the local canteen. On the last 3-4 days meals will be cooked on the team basis.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Khartsyzsk, Donetsk regionAt the free time volunteers will have an excursion around the town. There are rocks for climbing, paintball club and nice parks to visit. Volunteers can also visit Donetsk with a help of local youth.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is strictly forbidden on the project site. Smoking in front of children is not acceptable. We are waiting for volunteers who are interested to work with children, have good ideas and need space to implement them. Motivation letter is requiredTravel from Kiev to Donetsk takes around 12-14 hours by train over night. Staff of Alternative-V will help you in organizing your trip from Kiev to project site.  One-way ticket costs around 25 Euros.</descr_requirements><airport>DOK</airport><station>Donetsk</station><numvol_m>5</numvol_m><numvol_f>5</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>48.0422930</lat_project><lng_project>38.1460640</lng_project><notes></notes><lat_station>48.0158830</lat_station><lng_station>37.8028500</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="ed49c1c5b3117cc4fccfac89b69e2bb8                  "><code>ALT-14</code><project_type>TEE</project_type><work>SPOR,</work><start_date>2013-06-02</start_date><end_date>2013-06-16</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE FOR TEENAGERS I</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>14</min_age><max_age>16</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>10</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. Pine forest on the bank of picturesque river of the river creates an unforgettable atmosphere of living in nature.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>One of the main ideas of the camp is to teach through the practical work, making children s holiday active, entertaining, informative and helpful. The camp program is aimed not only at the organization of children s rest, but also on education of children. Learning is very various, from the basics of safe behavior to the training of leadership and oratory. Every child and teenager can find in the Forest Academy something really good for himself.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>in triple double-layer tents that protect from rain and insects. All tents are placed on pallets to raise them above the ground, so children are protected from moisture and dirt.Camp is ensured with uninterrupted water and power supply. Water from the source of Jurassic period is tested and certified according to the requirements of sanitary-epidemiological service.Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by campers (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire 4 times per day. We offer children to participate in cooking food to get so useful practical skills and making their own culinary experiments.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>Extra fee: 300 Euros.Remarks: On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>5</numvol_m><numvol_f>5</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>EXTRA FEE - 300 EUROS</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="304c24a509fd1b23df977754a8b8e5d9                  "><code>ALT-04</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-06-19</start_date><end_date>2013-07-02</end_date><name>SUMMER WITH ENGLISH I</name><location>KHARKIV</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>99</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>4</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>Sports summer centre  Boyko school  is situated in a picturesque place on the bank of the lake, 30 km from Kharkiv (second largest city in Ukraine and its first capital), eastern part of Ukraine. The Center was founded in 1987 on the territory of the former duke s estate. On the territory of the Center there is a pond with a lot of fish i so you can go fishing there. There also are stables with 12 horses, a riding school for children. The camp hosts about 200 children at a time. The camp works by the program of the summer English language school.</descr_partner> <descr_work>Each volunteer will be accommodated together with one Ukrainian leader in the camp next to children rooms. The main task of the volunteers will be to help in organising everyday life of the camp and leisure time activities, such as workshops, sport competitions, contests, activities connected with culture, history, traditions of the volunteers  countries. The volunteers will also assist teachers in teaching English in the course of lessons. Volunteers will not be provided with a ready plan for the lessons or activities. Everything is up to the volunteers. We expect from volunteers new ideas and enthusiasm in organising children s leisure time to make it meaningful and fun. Every volunteer must be ready to help children in organising the Day of Culture of the volunteer s country (national games, songs, dances, recipes of the national food i should be easy to cook). If you have experience, and most important - desire to work with children, this project is for YOU</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will be accommodated in rooms with 4 beds. Simple accommodation; toilet and shower with warm water are near the rooms. Food will be provided in the camp canteen three times a day.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>30 km from Kharkiv.  Kharkiv is the second largest city in Ukraine and its first capital. It can truly be named a Ukrainian megapolis. It is situated in North-East of Ukraine in the confluence of three rivers. Its population is 1 470 000 people. It is one of the biggest scientific and cultural centers. Kharkiv is the city of students and has 80 higher educational establishments. The city is famous for its great traditions and extraordinary historical past. In 2004 Kharkiv celebrated its 350th anniversary.  Here you can find some information about Kharkiv     http://www.kharkov.ua/index-e.phtmlLeisure Time: Lots of sport facilities are available, in the evening cultural meetings with the campers and staff will be organized, sightseeing, excursions around Kharkiv city, disco and everything what we will be able to create for ourselves to make our camp exciting.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>Dates of projects can vary by 1-2 days (precise dates will be confirmed at the beginning of April).</descr_requirements><airport>HRK</airport><station>Kharkiv</station><numvol_m>2</numvol_m><numvol_f>2</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>1</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>49.9935000</lat_project><lng_project>36.2303830</lng_project><notes></notes><lat_station>49.9935000</lat_station><lng_station>36.2303830</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="6b92ebaadfbe7d73707cbc697c01f121                  "><code>ALT-09</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-07-18</start_date><end_date>2013-08-01</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE IV</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>19</min_age><max_age>29</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>5</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. There is water and electricity on the project site. Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by children (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>we expect volunteers to be actively involved in the life of Scoutville. You will take part in administrating project site (checking accommodation facilities for children etc). International volunteers will help in organizing and leading clubs, workshops. If you have your own ideas what to suggest as a theme of a workshop/club/meeting i you are always welcome Please, mention your ideas for possible activities and your previous experience in motivation letter.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>volunteers will be accommodated in 2 tents (1 tent for 3 persons).  Food will be provided (or prepared by volunteers) three times per day.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is strictly forbidden on the project site. Smoking in front of children is not acceptable. We are waiting for volunteers who are interested to work with children, have good ideas and need space to implement them. Motivation letter is required Please, describe in ML which skills you want to share with campers.                   On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together with the campleader will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus, one way ticket cost i around 3 euro.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>2</numvol_m><numvol_f>3</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>Motivation letter is required</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="07e526991872f541348ac53cb56a8189                  "><code>ALT-02</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-06-07</start_date><end_date>2013-06-25</end_date><name>TOWARDS CHILDREN</name><location>VILLAGE PYATYKHATKY, KYIV REGION</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>19</min_age><max_age>30</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>5</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>educational camp )Zoryanyii works within the frames of Regional Complex Program to overcome children s negligence support of the poor families with children and reformation of the boarding schools. Camp takes place annually from 2008 and hosts around 200 children aged 8-16 years old. Educational camp  Zoryanyi  was established for children who grow in problematic environment: children deprived of parental care, homeless, and children from the families under the difficult living circumstances, children having problems with the law, orphans, and children from special institutions. For those children camp is the only possibility to spend time interestingly, in safe environment. International volunteers probably will be the first foreigners they meet with. We expect that experience of intercultural communication will widen horizons and enrich development of campers.</descr_partner> <descr_work>during summer camp children visit historical places, meet interesting people, compete, sing, dance, play, and find new friends. International volunteers together with Ukrainian educators, psychologists, social workers, students-volunteers who have experience in work with above mentioned children are supposed to plan and run activities for campers such as creative workshops in small groups, assisting in common camp activities, cultural events, sport events, sightseeing tours by bus and on foot. Campers will be divided into 6 groups, 25 persons in each.Possible activity themes: - organizing sports activities. Our motto: )I can do it and I will teach others do it i;- Playmaker (organizing of the games, games in the street, in the gym, national games). Motto is )Playing is the communication means and child socializationi.- Choreographer (ability to create and to lead dance classes, individual and collective dances). The motto is )I dance i dance togetheri.We are looking for motivated and enthusiastic volunteers, who are able to share their knowledge. The volunteer should be responsible, be able to work in team and be initiative. Camp shift will start on 10 of June and end on 24 of June, international volunteers should arrive earlier for preparation.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>in the building, 3-4 persons per room. Meals will be provided 4 times per day.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>village Pyatyhatky, Obukhiv district, Kyiv region (30 km from Kiev). Leisure time: activities in the group, intercultural learning, sightseeing tours, sport and cultural activities, picnics, swimming and paddling in river and everything what we will be able to create for ourselves to make our camp exciting.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is strictly forbidden on the project site. Smoking in front of children is not acceptable.  Motivation letter is required Please, describe in ML which skills you want to share with campers.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>2</numvol_m><numvol_f>3</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0529506</lat_project><lng_project>30.7667133</lng_project><notes>Motivation letter is required</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="c4356ba3e2cb1818e35bd081f6b9b14c                  "><code>ALT-16</code><project_type>TEE</project_type><work>SPOR,</work><start_date>2013-07-03</start_date><end_date>2013-07-17</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE FOR TEENAGERS III</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>14</min_age><max_age>16</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>10</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. Pine forest on the bank of picturesque river of the river creates an unforgettable atmosphere of living in nature.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>One of the main ideas of the camp is to teach through the practical work, making children s holiday active, entertaining, informative and helpful. The camp program is aimed not only at the organization of children s rest, but also on education of children. Learning is very various, from the basics of safe behavior to the training of leadership and oratory. Every child and teenager can find in the Forest Academy something really good for himself.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>in triple double-layer tents that protect from rain and insects. All tents are placed on pallets to raise them above the ground, so children are protected from moisture and dirt.Camp is ensured with uninterrupted water and power supply. Water from the source of Jurassic period is tested and certified according to the requirements of sanitary-epidemiological service.Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by campers (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire 4 times per day. We offer children to participate in cooking food to get so useful practical skills and making their own culinary experiments.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>Extra fee: 300 Euros.Remarks: On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>5</numvol_m><numvol_f>5</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>EXTRA FEE - 300 EUROS</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="8c605c747bdb02fbefc22e8a174537d8                  "><code>ALT-13</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>RENO,</work><start_date>2013-08-26</start_date><end_date>2013-09-08</end_date><name>POLTAVA</name><location>POLTAVA</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>18</min_age><max_age>30</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>12</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>Project partners: Educational Complex  Parostok  (UNESCO Associated School).Project: the project will be held in Poltava, Central Ukraine, for the second time. The city is historically known for the remarkable battle which took place near the city between Russian and Swedish armies during the Northern War in 1709. Some historians agree that Poltava battle marked the end of the Swedish Empire and birth of the Russian Empire.      Poltava is a beautiful town with about 300,000 residents. It s filled with green parks, historical monuments, fountains, restaurants and cafes.       Parostok is an educational complex founded in 1994 to provide its students with more than a school education. It strives to raise the children in a well-rounded, caring and educational environment. International volunteers will work together with school children.      Main component of the project is intercultural exchange between international participants and local schoolchildren and students. Based on previous year experience we decide to dedicate more time and efforts to this part of workcamp. We plan to involve schoolchildren and student from wide numbers of Poltava s schools and Universities. International volunteers will prepare and run presentations of their countries and educational systems especially.</descr_partner> <descr_work>we invite volunteers for a wonderful intercultural exchange with our school children (10-17 years old). During first half of the day volunteers will help maintain and beautify the town areas by engaging such project as renovation of children s playground. Playgroud is situated in populous blockhouse areas of Poltava. Playground is used by local children, two nearby kindergartens and school  Parostok . Now playground is in poor condition. Organisers plan with the help of sponsor (who will donate materials and tools) and international volunteers to renovate and to decorate playground. Your ideas are welcomed           In the second half of the day volunteers will prepare and run presentations of their countries, traditions with the schoolchildren and local volunteers. In these cultural exchanges, we can learn about your country s popular games, sports, dances and songs, recipes and about educational system. Content and format of presentations will be created by volunteers.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>volunteers will stay in dormitory with all facilities. Breakfast will be prepared by volunteers. Lunch and dinner will be provided in school canteen.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location:  Poltava, Poltava region. Leisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer. On the weekends, you will have free time for sightseeing in Poltava, visiting museums and a festival park, ice-skating, bowling, playing sports, dancing, and sunbathing and swimming on Poltava local beach.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is not welcomed on the project.                  On first day of the project (26.08.2013) volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kyiv and together with the campleader travel to project site. Trip will take 4 hours by bus or train, one way ticket costs around 15 euro.</descr_requirements><airport>PLV</airport><station>Poltava</station><numvol_m>6</numvol_m><numvol_f>6</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>49.5882670</lat_project><lng_project>34.5514170</lng_project><notes></notes><lat_station>49.5882670</lat_station><lng_station>34.5514170</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="23a8815c83e3d6a78a711038971e5d9e                  "><code>ALT-17</code><project_type>TEE</project_type><work>SPOR,</work><start_date>2013-07-18</start_date><end_date>2013-08-01</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE FOR TEENAGERS IV</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>14</min_age><max_age>16</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>10</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. Pine forest on the bank of picturesque river of the river creates an unforgettable atmosphere of living in nature.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>One of the main ideas of the camp is to teach through the practical work, making children s holiday active, entertaining, informative and helpful. The camp program is aimed not only at the organization of children s rest, but also on education of children. Learning is very various, from the basics of safe behavior to the training of leadership and oratory. Every child and teenager can find in the Forest Academy something really good for himself.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>in triple double-layer tents that protect from rain and insects. All tents are placed on pallets to raise them above the ground, so children are protected from moisture and dirt.Camp is ensured with uninterrupted water and power supply. Water from the source of Jurassic period is tested and certified according to the requirements of sanitary-epidemiological service.Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by campers (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire 4 times per day. We offer children to participate in cooking food to get so useful practical skills and making their own culinary experiments.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>Extra fee: 300 Euros.Remarks: On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>5</numvol_m><numvol_f>5</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>EXTRA FEE - 300 EUROS</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project><project id="8e98308384e02f668d4c0349af00ef9e                  "><code>ALT-06</code><project_type>STV</project_type><work>KIDS,</work><start_date>2013-07-03</start_date><end_date>2013-07-17</end_date><name>SCOUTVILLE III</name><location>PEREYASLAV-KHMELNYTSKYI</location><country>UKR</country><region></region><languages>eng,eng</languages><extrafee>.00</extrafee><extrafee_currency>UAH</extrafee_currency><min_age>19</min_age><max_age>29</max_age><disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols><numvol>5</numvol><vegetarian></vegetarian><family>0</family><description> </description><descr_partner>This year will be the fourth year when youth organization  Kyiv Scouts  organizes the children camp  Forest village Scoutville . The camp is situated on picturesque banks of Kaniv artificial sea in the pine forest. The nearest town i Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi and the camp is situated 120 km from Kyiv i capital of Ukraine. Camp is based in tents in pine forest. There is water and electricity on the project site. Special hygienic zones are equipped with showers and toilets. Food is prepared by children (with the help of instructors and cooks) on open fire.     The program of camp is based on Scouts methods, which provide overall development of the children. Program includes developing games, hiking trips, different sport competitions, additional educational courses (in scouts sphere), excursion program in National open-air museum  Pereyaslav . The team of foreign volunteers will work in close cooperation with pedagogical staff of the camp (teachers, psychologists, instructors of physical culture and sport, engineers).Join us and you will understand where the summer lives</descr_partner> <descr_work>we expect volunteers to be actively involved in the life of Scoutville. You will take part in administrating project site (checking accommodation facilities for children etc). International volunteers will help in organizing and leading clubs, workshops. If you have your own ideas what to suggest as a theme of a workshop/club/meeting i you are always welcome Please, mention your ideas for possible activities and your previous experience in motivation letter.</descr_work><descr_accomodation_and_food>volunteers will be accommodated in 2 tents (1 tent for 3 persons).  Food will be provided (or prepared by volunteers) three times per day.</descr_accomodation_and_food><descr_location_and_leisure>Location: near Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyi, UkraineLeisure time: Ukraine is a wonderful place to visit during the summer.  There are 17 museums and 7 magnificent parks in Pereyaslav-Khmelnytskyy, so volunteers will enjoy this place. Well-known in Ukraine - Open-air Museum of Folk Architecture is situated in Pereyaslav. Here you can see, among other things, authentic peasant huts of the times of old, smithies and several windmills of the eighteenth century. In fact, a village of the 17thi19th centuries is recreated. On the territory of the open-air museum, you can find other museums, one of which exhibits stone idols of the Scythian times of centuries before Christ.</descr_location_and_leisure><descr_requirements>alcohol is strictly forbidden on the project site. Smoking in front of children is not acceptable. We are waiting for volunteers who are interested to work with children, have good ideas and need space to implement them. Motivation letter is required Please, describe in ML which skills you want to share with campers.                   On first day of the project volunteers will meet in the office of Alternative-V in Kiev and together with the campleader will travel to the project site. Trip will take 2 hours by bus, one way ticket cost i around 3 euro.</descr_requirements><airport>KBP</airport><station>Kyiv</station><numvol_m>2</numvol_m><numvol_f>3</numvol_f><max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country><max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers><max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols><lat_project>50.0661111</lat_project><lng_project>31.4422222</lng_project><notes>Motivation letter is required</notes><lat_station>50.4501000</lat_station><lng_station>30.5234000</lng_station><bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi></project></projects></projectform>