<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<projectform>
	<network>Alliance</network>
	<application>E-vet</application>
	<date_filed>2013-03-02</date_filed>
	<version>1.0</version>
	<pef_send_by>VOC  Zana</pef_send_by>
	<pef_sender_email>workcamps@zid.org.me</pef_sender_email>
	<organization>Volunteer center ADP- Zid</organization>
	<organization_code>VOC</organization_code>
	<projects>
		<project id="deedbe6390eca11009c7884ed91a9a54                  ">
			<code>VOC 05</code>
			<project_type>STV</project_type>
			<work>RENO,</work>
			<start_date>2013-09-01</start_date>
			<end_date>2013-09-10</end_date>
			<name>COMMUNITY LIFE</name>
			<location>ULICNJ</location>
			<country>MNE</country>
			<region/>
			<languages>eng,eng</languages>
			<extrafee>25.00</extrafee>
			<extrafee_currency>EUR</extrafee_currency>
			<min_age>18</min_age>
			<max_age>28</max_age>
			<disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols>
			<numvol>10</numvol>
			<vegetarian/>
			<family>0</family>
			<description/>
			<descr_partner>Ulicnj Municipality</descr_partner>
			<descr_work>The project will take place in Ulcinj, south of Montenegro. Topic of workcamp is reconstruction of running truck.Description of the work: Volunteers will be work on running truck reconstruction and kid s playground.</descr_work>
			<descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will be hosted in public buildings (schools or other structures). They will prepare the food by themselves.  Sleeping bags are requirement.</descr_accomodation_and_food>
			<descr_location_and_leisure>during the free time, camp leader will organize excursions in the surrounding areas, swimming in the sea, during the night will be possible to go in the town for spend some time in pubs and locals.  Landscape/surrounding: Ulcinj is the southernmost city at Montenegrin coast. With its natural potential Ulcinj is tourism borne. The longest beach at the Adriatic sea i Velika Plaza that is 13 km long, the Ada Bojana i a unique river island with marvellous sandy beaches, Valdanos i a unique bay with a coastline covered in old olive trees, the reconstructed old city of Ulcinj i full of interesting restaurants, cafes, galleries and hotels- and many other attractive sights make Ulcinj unique and attractive for many tourists. Ulcinj is a city that you have to visit.</descr_location_and_leisure>
			<descr_requirements>Volunteers have to take sleeping bag, working clothes, swimming suite, also they can bring typical staffs (food, clothes, music...) from their country.</descr_requirements>
			<airport>TGD</airport>
			<station>Bar</station>
			<numvol_m>5</numvol_m>
			<numvol_f>5</numvol_f>
			<max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country>
			<max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers>
			<max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols>
			<lat_project>41.9297220</lat_project>
			<lng_project>19.2242910</lng_project>
			<notes>Volunteers should provide their own health and accident insurance. </notes>
			<lat_station>44.1885670</lat_station>
			<lng_station>2.0763310</lng_station>
			<bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi>
		</project>
		<project id="0cce3937ec1e21f5f9f527bad4f40a94                  ">
			<code>VOC 03</code>
			<project_type>STV</project_type>
			<work>DISA,</work>
			<start_date>2013-08-10</start_date>
			<end_date>2013-08-20</end_date>
			<name>CREATIVE TIME</name>
			<location>NIKSIC</location>
			<country>MNE</country>
			<region/>
			<languages>eng,eng</languages>
			<extrafee>25.00</extrafee>
			<extrafee_currency>EUR</extrafee_currency>
			<min_age>18</min_age>
			<max_age>28</max_age>
			<disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols>
			<numvol>7</numvol>
			<vegetarian/>
			<family>0</family>
			<description/>
			<descr_partner>Udruzenje za pomoc licima ometenim u psihofizickom razvoju, Niksic</descr_partner>
			<descr_work>Theme/project: The project will take place in upa Niksi263;ka near to Niksi263;, central part of Montenegro. Increase the confidence of young people with physical disabilities and make influence on reduce of prejudice and there socialization through realization of creative workshops.Description of the work: During the camp, volunteers will taking part in creative workshops with children with disabilities, they will do personal assistance, outdoor activities, drawing, singing and painting...</descr_work>
			<descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will be hosted in schools, sleeping in sleaping bags. They will prepare the food by themselves.</descr_accomodation_and_food>
			<descr_location_and_leisure>During the free time, camp leader will organize excursions in the surrounding areas, hiking on mountains and surrounding hills, trip to the neighbouring. During the camp will be organised visit to Ethno Village Piva and Monastery Konak.Landscape/surrounding: Niksi263; (pronounced [n.k643;it865;597;) is the second largest city in Montenegro, after Podgorica, and is an important industrial, cultural, and educational center. Although Niksi263; area has seen human settlements since antiquity, most of the modern Niksi263; is a planned city. Very little remains of the Ottoman architectural heritage, despite the long presence of Ottoman Empire in the area. The city layout visible today still follows the 1883 urban plan commissioned by King Nicholas and designed by Croatian architect Josip Slade. According to this plan, the streets of Niksi263; radiate to the north and east from the central city square (today a roundabout), locally known as Skver. The radial streets are intersected by circumferential streets and avenues, thus creating a half-spider web-like street layout.Layers of different architectural styles and urban patterns are evident along the radial network of streets. Thus, closest to the central roundabout is the historical core of Niksi263;, formed after the liberation from Ottoman Empire, and serving as a nucleus for Slade s urban plan. This area, on the foot of Trebjesa Hill, is home to King Nicholas Palace, City Park, and Freedom Square, main city square located along the central Njegoseva Street. The area is composed of mostly single or two storey row housing with basic designs, an architecture typical for late 19th and early 20th centuries Montenegro. The roundabout and the surrounding area is still the focal point of activities in the city, as bus and train stations, as well as commercial and civic services are located in the area. More information: www.niksic.me</descr_location_and_leisure>
			<descr_requirements>Volunteers have to take working clothes, warm clothes (mountains nights could be cold), also they can bring typical staffs (food, music...) from their country.</descr_requirements>
			<airport>TGD</airport>
			<station>Podgorica</station>
			<numvol_m>3</numvol_m>
			<numvol_f>4</numvol_f>
			<max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country>
			<max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers>
			<max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols>
			<lat_project>42.7732810</lat_project>
			<lng_project>18.9441600</lng_project>
			<notes>Volunteers should provide their own health and accident insurance</notes>
			<lat_station>42.4425750</lat_station>
			<lng_station>19.2686460</lng_station>
			<bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi>
		</project>
		<project id="a3d08e4b7e568cd0bb9c835865c44693                  ">
			<code>VOC 04</code>
			<project_type>STV</project_type>
			<work>RENO,</work>
			<start_date>2013-08-20</start_date>
			<end_date>2013-08-30</end_date>
			<name>COMMUNITY LIFE</name>
			<location>ULCINJ</location>
			<country>MNE</country>
			<region/>
			<languages>eng,eng</languages>
			<extrafee>25.00</extrafee>
			<extrafee_currency>EUR</extrafee_currency>
			<min_age>18</min_age>
			<max_age>28</max_age>
			<disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols>
			<numvol>10</numvol>
			<vegetarian/>
			<family>0</family>
			<description/>
			<descr_partner>Municipality Ulcinj</descr_partner>
			<descr_work>The project will take place in Ulcinj, south of Montenegro. Topic of workcamp is reconstruction of running truck.Description of the work: Volunteers will be work on running truck reconstruction and kid s playground.</descr_work>
			<descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will be hosted in public buildings (schools or other structures). They will prepare the food by themselves.  Sleeping bags are required.</descr_accomodation_and_food>
			<descr_location_and_leisure>during the free time, camp leader will organize excursions in the surrounding areas, swimming in the sea, during the night will be possible to go in the town for spend some time in pubs and locals.  Landscape/surrounding: Ulcinj is the southernmost city at Montenegrin coast. With its natural potential Ulcinj is tourism borne. The longest beach at the Adriatic sea i Velika Plaza that is 13 km long, the Ada Bojana i a unique river island with marvellous sandy beaches, Valdanos i a unique bay with a coastline covered in old olive trees, the reconstructed old city of Ulcinj i full of interesting restaurants, cafes, galleries and hotels- and many other attractive sights make Ulcinj unique and attractive for many tourists. Ulcinj is a city that you have to visit.</descr_location_and_leisure>
			<descr_requirements>Volunteers have to take sleeping bag, working clothes, swimming suite, also they can bring typical staffs (food, clothes, music...) from their country.</descr_requirements>
			<airport>TGD</airport>
			<station>Bar</station>
			<numvol_m>5</numvol_m>
			<numvol_f>5</numvol_f>
			<max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country>
			<max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers>
			<max_national_vols>0</max_national_vols>
			<lat_project>41.9297220</lat_project>
			<lng_project>19.2242910</lng_project>
			<notes>Volunteers should provide their own health and accident insurance. </notes>
			<lat_station>44.1885670</lat_station>
			<lng_station>2.0763310</lng_station>
			<bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi>
		</project>
		<project id="871b5c6578cb337ba5050cde94e1d169                  ">
			<code>VOC 01</code>
			<project_type>STV</project_type>
			<work>ENVI,</work>
			<start_date>2013-06-25</start_date>
			<end_date>2013-07-05</end_date>
			<name>LIKE LAKE</name>
			<location>PLJEVLJA</location>
			<country>MNE</country>
			<region/>
			<languages>eng,eng</languages>
			<extrafee>25.00</extrafee>
			<extrafee_currency>EUR</extrafee_currency>
			<min_age>18</min_age>
			<max_age>40</max_age>
			<disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols>
			<numvol>10</numvol>
			<vegetarian/>
			<family>0</family>
			<description/>
			<descr_partner>NGO - Da zazivi selo</descr_partner>
			<descr_work>The project will take place in Pljevlja, north part of Montenegro. The volunteers will be worked on cleaning and removing the waste around the Borovica Lake.Description of the work: Volunteers will be cleaning the area around Borovica Lake, removing the waste all along the shores of Lake. Working hours will be about 5/6 per day.</descr_work>
			<descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will be hosted in public building (schools or other structures) with toilets and showers. Sleeping in sleeping bags (Volunteers have to take sleeping bag). Volunteers will prepare the food by themselves.</descr_accomodation_and_food>
			<descr_location_and_leisure>During the free time, camp leader will organize excursions in the surrounding areas, hiking on mountains and surrounding hills, trip to the neighbouring, during the night will be possible to go in the town for spend some time in pubs and locals.  Landscape/surrounding: Pljevlja (pronounced [p654;603;770;v798;654;a) is a town and municipality located in the northern part of Montenegro. In 2003, the municipality of Pljevlja had a population of 36,918, while the city itself had a population of about 21,000. The municipality borders those of abljak, Bijelo Polje and Mojkovac in Montenegro, as well as the republics of Serbia and Bosnia and Herzegovina. With a total area of 1,346 km2 (520 sq mi), it is the third largest municipality in Montenegro. Sights: Husein-pasa s mosque with the tallest minaret (42m) in the Balkans; Monastery of Holy Trinity; the Roman city Municipium; the oldest high school in Montenegro (Tanasije Pejatovi263; High School)... More information: www.pljevlja.me</descr_location_and_leisure>
			<descr_requirements>Volunteers have to take sleeping bag, working clothes, warm clothes (mountains nights could be cold), also they can bring typical staffs (food, music...) from their country. Volunteers should provide their own health and accident insurance</descr_requirements>
			<airport>TGD</airport>
			<station>Bijelo Polje</station>
			<numvol_m>5</numvol_m>
			<numvol_f>5</numvol_f>
			<max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country>
			<max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers>
			<max_national_vols>2</max_national_vols>
			<lat_project>43.3600000</lat_project>
			<lng_project>19.3600000</lng_project>
			<notes>Will be conformed till 2013/04/15 Volunteers should provide their own health and accident insurance</notes>
			<lat_station>43.0377080</lat_station>
			<lng_station>19.7479310</lng_station>
			<bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi>
		</project>
		<project id="6d72d0e7ff04ec673b6521a72892dde2                  ">
			<code>VOC 02</code>
			<project_type>STV</project_type>
			<work>AGRI,</work>
			<start_date>2013-07-07</start_date>
			<end_date>2013-07-15</end_date>
			<name>SURVIVE IN NATURE</name>
			<location>ZABLJAK</location>
			<country>MNE</country>
			<region/>
			<languages>eng,eng</languages>
			<extrafee>25.00</extrafee>
			<extrafee_currency>EUR</extrafee_currency>
			<min_age>18</min_age>
			<max_age>28</max_age>
			<disabled_vols>0</disabled_vols>
			<numvol>10</numvol>
			<vegetarian/>
			<family>0</family>
			<description/>
			<descr_partner>NGO Opstanak</descr_partner>
			<descr_work>The project will take place in Vrela near to abljak and Pljevlja, north part of Montenegro. The volunteers will be learning about medicinal herbs and they will prepare mini herbs garden.Description of the work: During the camp, volunteers will learn to distinguish between herbs, of which will make a small medicinal plants nursery. They will learn that which are honey producing plants and obtain basic theoretical knowledge about beekeeping. Working hours will be about 5per day.</descr_work>
			<descr_accomodation_and_food>Volunteers will be hosted in old village schools, sleeping in sleeping bags (Volunteers have to take sleeping bag). They will prepare the food by themselves. There is no drinking water in the building. Volunteers will be brining water from wellspring, less than 100 m far away from the school. There is montage showers in school, toilets are beside the school.</descr_accomodation_and_food>
			<descr_location_and_leisure>During the free time, camp leader will organize excursions in the surrounding areas, hiking on mountains and surrounding hills, trip to the neighbouring. On the 13/07 will be organized visit to the biggest village fair in the Montenegro. Landscape/surrounding: Village Vrela is located between Pljevlja and abljak. Vrala is part of the most beautiful our National Park, Dumitor. Dr. John Luci originates from this region. Biologists and can find endemic species of plants and amphibians unique in this region. In a radius of 10 km are three beautiful lakes Black, Zminje and Zmijsko. More information: www.pljevlja.me and www.zabljak.me</descr_location_and_leisure>
			<descr_requirements>Volunteers have to take sleeping bag, working clothes, warm clothes (mountains nights could be cold), also they can bring typical staffs (food, music...) from their country.</descr_requirements>
			<airport>TGD</airport>
			<station>Bijelo Polje</station>
			<numvol_m>5</numvol_m>
			<numvol_f>5</numvol_f>
			<max_vols_per_country>2</max_vols_per_country>
			<max_teenagers>0</max_teenagers>
			<max_national_vols>2</max_national_vols>
			<lat_project>43.1545410</lat_project>
			<lng_project>19.1231500</lng_project>
			<notes>Will be conformed till 2013/04/15 Volunteers should provide their own health and accident insurance</notes>
			<lat_station>43.0377080</lat_station>
			<lng_station>19.7479310</lng_station>
			<bi_tri_multi>0</bi_tri_multi>
		</project>
	</projects>
</projectform>